(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.2",
"generated_at": "2026-08-31T01:03:09.402975",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
○○初お披露目!? 重大発表!? コラボ3D LIVE!! 超生誕祭2021
First reveal!? Major announcement!? Collab 3D LIVE!! Super Birthday Festival 2021
ピーンポーンパンポーン
*Ding-dong, chime-chime*
皆さん こんばんは！
Good evening, everyone!
チビアズです！
I'm Chibiazu!
今から影ナレを読みたいと思います！
I'm going to read the pre-show announcement now!
えーっと、本日は「あずき超生誕祭」にお越しいただき、ありがとうございます！
Um... Thank you very much for attending today's "Azuki Super Birthday Festival"!
開演に先立ちまして、ご来場のお客様にお願い申し上げます。
Before the show begins, we have a few requests for our audience.
ただいまより、公演が始まります。
The performance will begin shortly.
是非みなさま、コメントやSNSで一緒に盛り上がってください！
Please enjoy the show and get hyped together in the comments and on social media!
ハッシュタグは、「#あずき超生誕祭2021」です！
The hashtag is "#AzukiSuperBirthdayFestival2021"!
たくさんスクショしてくれると、嬉しいです！
I'd be super happy if you take lots of screenshots!
じゃあ、チビアズはおうちに帰って寝ます！
Well then, Chibiazu is going home to sleep!
バイバーイ！
Bye-bye!
同じ未来を見ていた
I wanted to see the same future,
あの夢手にしたい
I want to hold that dream in my hands.
それぞれ違った心で走れ go
With our different hearts, let's run, go!
どこを見ても真っ暗な場所に芽生えてた
Even in pitch-dark places, a sprout of hope was born,
ほんの小さな希望にこの瞳奪われた
capturing my eyes with just a tiny bit of hope.
不安で揺れる心をうまくチューニングして
Tuning my trembling, anxious heart just right,
ほんの小さな勇気を振り絞っていたよ
I gathered up just a tiny bit of courage.
諦めの文字デリートして進む
Deleting thoughts of giving up as I move forward,
苦しいときも、もう私は
even in painful times, I am no longer...
ひとりじゃないから
...alone anymore,
だからもっと夢追いかけたい
so I want to chase my dreams even more,
ワクワク止まらない
with unstoppable excitement.
想像超えてく世界見せてあげる
I'll show you a world beyond imagination.
アクセスしてみたい後悔なんてそうさせない
I want to try accessing it, I won't let you have any regrets.
それぞれ違った心で走れ go
With our different hearts, let's run, go!
仮想の空に輝く眩しい想いは
The dazzling feelings shining in the virtual sky
見たことのない光を現実に届けるよ
bring a never-before-seen light into reality.
いつも聞こえるエールはここにキャプチャーして
Capturing the cheers we always hear right here,
また新しい光を探したくなるよ
makes us want to search for a new light once again.
君の笑顔は保存して進む
Saving your smile as I move forward,
苦しいときも振り返るよ力湧くから
looking back in tough times because it gives me strength.
胸を張って夢追いかけたい奇跡の物語
Walking proudly, I want to chase my dreams—a miraculous story
一緒に作ろう終わらない夢を誰一人欠かせない愛が舞い込んだこの世界
we'll create together, an endless dream in this world where love blossoms without a single person missing.
それぞれ違った心で彩れ
Colored by our respective, different hearts.
悲しいときも寂しいときも信じ合えるものがある
Even when sad, even when lonely, there are things we can believe in together.
忘れずにこの鼓動鳴らし続けたい終わらない世界に溢れ出るよ笑顔達
I want to keep this heartbeat ringing without forgetting, overflowing into an endless world with smiles.
憧れの舞台立ちたいらしく輝きたいときに涙してまた笑い合いたい
Wanting to stand on the stage of our dreams, wanting to shine brightly, crying and laughing together again.
同じ未来を見たいあの夢手にしたい踏み出そう奇跡の一歩を
Wanting to see the same future, wanting to hold that dream in our hands, let's take a miraculous first step.
息切らし て夢追いかけたい
Out of breath, I want to chase my dreams,
ワクワク止まらない
with unstoppable excitement.
想像超えてく世界見せてあげる
I'll show you a world beyond imagination.
アクセスしてみたいな后悔なんてここにない
I want to try accessing it, there are no regrets here.
それぞれ違った心で走れ go
With our different hearts, let's run, go!
息切らし て夢追いかけたい
Out of breath, I want to chase my dreams,
ワクワク止まらない
with unstoppable excitement.
想像超えてく世界見せてあげる
I'll show you a world beyond imagination.
アクセスしてみたいな后悔なんてここにない
I want to try accessing it, there are no regrets here.
それぞれ違った心で作るわ
We'll create it with our different hearts.
はい、あらためましてこあずきー！
Yes, once again, I'm KOAZKI!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
えー今日はですね、AZKi超生誕祭2021にお越しいただきありがとうございますー！
Um, thank you so much for coming to AZKi's Super Birthday Festival 2021 today!
やあー！
Yay!
ということで、今日はですね、なんと、なんと今日お二人に来てきまして、じゃまずちょっと挨拶をぜひお願いします！
So, today, amazingly, amazingly, two guests came here today, so first of all, please give us a greeting!
わため！
Watame!
ほら来ないめよきせ、角巻わためです！
Horaimen Yokise, Tsunomaki Watame!
こんばんはーどうもこんばんはー！
Good evening, hello everyone!
あれちびあずちゃんは？
Wait, where's Chibi AZKi?
違う違う、そっちのオープニングでしょ？
No, no, that's for the opening, right?
よろしくお願いします！
Please treat us well!
ありがとう来てくれてありがとう！
Thank you so much for coming!
みんな楽しもうね！
Let's all have fun!
そしてねねち！ はーい！
And Nenechi! - Here!
ほろらいぶごきせい、オレンジ担当の桃鈴ねねです！よろしくお願いします！
Hololive 5th Gen, orange rep Momosuzu Nene! Nice to meet you!
お姉ちゃん呼んでくれてありがとう！
Thank you for inviting me, big sister!
来てくれてありがとうございます！
Thank you very much for coming!
あの、今日はね、AZKiの生誕配信ということでですね
Um, today is AZKi's birthday stream, so...
お近くで、間近で…間近で…
Up close, right up close...
間近で…
Right up close...
まじか…AZKi、そうですね、今日はAZKi担当です！
Seriously... AZKi, that's right, I'm in charge of AZKi today!
あのちょっと大先輩、大先輩ねねおじと…ねねおじの…大先輩わたおじがいるんですけど…
Um, big senior Nene-oji... and big senior Wata-oji are here...
今日はAZKiも出していきたいと思っております！
But today I want to bring out AZKi too, I think!
えっと…近くで本当にライブを見たい2人をお呼びしてですね、今日は一番いい席で…
We invited two people who really want to watch the live up close, so today, from the best seat...
見てくれよ…見てもらえるのかな？頼むよ…
Look at me... Will you look at me? Please...
2人を、2人を隅々まで楽しんで行きたいと思っております！
We want to enjoy both of them to every nook and cranny!
みんなもね、最後までぜひライブを見ていってくださいね！
Everyone, please keep watching the live until the very end!
今日は二人ともありがとー！
Thank you both so much today!
こちらこそ、おめでとう！本当にありがとう！
Thank you too, congratulations! Thank you so much!
よろしくお願いします！
Please treat us well!
早速ですね、ここからソロパートに、もう、もう見ていきますよ！
Now then, from here on, we're going into the solo parts, we're going to watch them right away!
ということで、トップバッターは、まずはねねちから！
So, top batter, first is Nenechi!
やるぞー！お前らかましていってください！
Let's do it! Everyone, go wild!
息をなるべく切らさないように頑張ります！可愛く…
I'll do my best not to run out of breath as much as possible! Stay cute...
それでは、ではよろしくお願いします！
Well then, please treat us well!
はーい、じゃあね、二人もね、特等席でね…見てるよ！
Right, well then, you two are in special seats... We're watching!
頑張ってね！だって思いのほか特等席なんだもん！
Do your best! Because it's surprisingly a special seat!
そう、みんな後ろに椅子があるんですけど…特等席で我々見ておりますので！
Yes, there are chairs in the back for everyone... so we are watching from special seats!
ねね頑張って！がんばるぞー！
Nene, do your best! Let's do our best!
それでは、まずはこの曲からお聞きください、「ランチタイム」！
Well then, first please listen to this song, "Lunch with me"!
遙か起きた朝は なんだか いつもより眠くて
Waking up far earlier than usual, I feel sleepier than ever.
昨日の夜ずっとマンガを読んでたら眠れなくってさ
I stayed up all night reading manga and couldn't sleep at all.
今頃そっちはどこで何をしてるかななんて
Wondering where and what you might be doing right now...
考えてたら心がふわっとかるくなるんだ
Thinking about it makes my heart feel so light and fluffy.
これは内緒なんだけど昨日読んだマンガの
This is a secret, but the protagonist of the manga I read yesterday...
主人公に君がちょっと似てたんだよ
looked a little bit like you.
ねえお昼お昼お昼お昼お昼お昼一緒に
Hey, let's have lunch, lunch, lunch together!
お昼お昼お昼お昼お昼お昼食べよう
Let's have lunch together at noon!
ちょっとだけ同じ気持ち共有したくて
I just wanted to share this little feeling with you.
そうお昼お昼お昼お昼お昼お昼だけでも
Even if it's just for lunch, lunch, lunch...
全然特別なことじゃなくてもいつもの君でいいんだよ 一緒に食べよう
It's nothing special at all, you can just be your usual self. Let's eat together!
決してリア充とは言えない地味な日々だけど
My days are plain, far from being a social butterfly, but
なぜだろう最近は少しキラキラなんだ
for some reason, lately they sparkle a little bit.
どんなに直前にいやなことあっても
No matter how awful things happen right before,
君に会えると思うとによけちゃってさ
just thinking about meeting you makes me so happy.
ねえお昼お昼お昼お昼お昼お昼一緒に
Hey, let's have lunch, lunch, lunch together!
お昼お昼お昼お昼お昼お昼食べよう
Let's have lunch together at noon!
ひとりよりきっと楽しくなるから
It's bound to be much more fun than being alone!
そうお昼お昼お昼お昼お昼お昼だけだし
That's right, even if it's just for lunch...
ななななな「な」じゃなくて
Not na-na-na-na-na, it's "na"!
ににににに「に」じゃなくて
ni-ni-ni-ni-ni, it's "ni"!
ぬぬぬぬぬ「ぬ」じゃなくて
nu-nu-nu-nu-nu, it's "nu"!
ののののの「の」じゃなくて
no-no-no-no-no, it's "no"!
……ねっ！
...ne!
（ねねっ！）
(Ne-ne!)
（ヨイショ ヨイショ ヨイショ ヨイショ！）
(Yoisho, yoisho, yoisho, yoisho!)
こんねね～！（こんねね～！）
Konnene~! (Konnene~!)
ホロライブ5期生 オレンジ担当
Hololive 5th generation's orange representative,
桃鈴ねで…あっ、桃鈴ねねですっ！（ねねち～！）
Momosuzu Ne— ah, Momosuzu Nene! (Nenechi~!)
異世界から来ました
Coming from another world,
アイドル志望の
Dreaming of becoming an idol,
新人VTuber（何だって！？）
A new VTuber! (What!?)
まぁ、とにもかくにも明るくいきましょう！
Well, let's stay bright and cheerful no matter what!
ちょっとくらい緊張したって、滑ったって
Even if I get a little nervous or stumble,
「うおーっ！」って感じでさ（うおーっ！）
Shouting "Whoa!" (Whoa!)
「どりゃあっ！」っていこう（どりゃあっ！）
And going "Ha!" (Ha!)
あきらめの悪さは長所だよね？
Refusing to give up is one of my strong points, right?
ねねねねねねねねね！（ねっ！）
ne-ne-ne-ne-ne-ne-ne-ne-ne! (Ne!)
「はぁ～ん」な事もあるけど
Sometimes things make me go "Haa-n"
悔しい事もあるけど大丈夫！（大丈夫！）
And sometimes it's frustrating, but it's alright! (Alright!)
今日もしっかりおめかしして
Dressing up nicely today too,
いつかはきっと「すーぱーねねちー！」
And someday becoming super Nenechi!
ついてきて、
Come along with me,
ねねねねねねねねねねねねねねねねねねねねねねねねねねねねねねねねねねね
ne-ne-ne-ne-ne-ne-ne-ne-ne-ne...
って、全力でいこう！
And go at full power!
そうで全開でいこう！
That's right, let's go full throttle!
思い切りやれば何とかなるよ
If I give it my all, it'll somehow work out.
ポンコツだっていい（ヨイショ！）
Even if I'm clumsy, it's okay! (Yoisho!)
誤字だっていい（ヨイショ！）
Even if I make a typo, it's okay! (Yoisho!)
ただ駆け抜けていこうね
I'll just keep running through!
（ね！ね！ね！ね！）
(Ne! Ne! Ne! Ne!)
大爆走（ねねっ！）
Daibakusou! (Nene!)
（ヨイショ ヨイショ ヨイショ ヨイショ！）
(Yoisho, yoisho, yoisho, yoisho!)
野菜ジュースと炭酸とお菓子、そろえて準備OK！
Veggie juice, fizzy drinks, and sweets, got them all ready OK!
でも朝は苦手（だねっ！）
But I'm not a morning person (right!)
夜も苦手（だねっ！）
And not a night person either (right!)
やっぱり睡眠って、大事だよね？
Sleeping really is important, huh?
ねねねねねねねねねね（ねっ！）
ne-ne-ne-ne-ne-ne-ne-ne-ne-ne! (Ne!)
たくさんの人に、愛されたいっ！
I want to be loved by lots of people!
ちゅちゅちゅっ（ちゅちゅちゅっ）
Chu chu chu! (Chu chu chu!)
大好きなみんなに、愛されたいっ！
I want to be loved by my beloved everyone!
ちゅちゅちゅっ（ちゅちゅちゅっ）
Chu chu chu! (Chu chu chu!)
そしたらなるんだ「はいぱーねねちー！」
And then I'll become hyper Nenechi!
やっちゃってねねねねねね…
Let's do it, ne-ne-ne-ne...
って、全力でいこう！
And go at full power!
そうで全開でいこう！
Yep, let's go at full throttle!
歌は誰にも負けたくないんだ
I don't wanna lose to anyone in singing!
大きい声で（ヨイショ！）
With a loud voice (Yoisho!)
あ、その前に（ヨイショ！）
Ah, before that (Yoisho!)
ちょっとトイレ行ってくるね
I'll go to the restroom real quick~
(restroom time!!!)
（ねっ！）（ヨイショ ヨイショ ヨイショ ヨイショ！）
(Ne!)(Yoisho, yoisho, yoisho, yoisho!)
ただいま～！
I'm back~!
最後に
And finally...
ねねねねねねねねねね（ねねっ！）
ne-ne-ne-ne-ne-ne-ne-ne-ne-ne... (Nene!)
って、全力でいこう！
And go at full power!
そうで全開でいこう！
Yep, let's go at full throttle!
思い切りやれば何とかなるよ
If I give it my all, it'll somehow work out.
ポンコツだっていい（ヨイショ！）
Even if I'm clumsy, it's okay! (Yoisho!)
誤字だっていい（ヨイショ！）
Even if I make a typo, it's okay! (Yoisho!)
ただ駆け抜けていこうね
I'll just keep running through!
（ねっ！ねっ！ねっ！ねっ！）
(Ne! Ne! Ne! Ne!)
大爆走（ねねっ！）
Daibakusou! (Nene!)
野菜ジュースと炭酸とお菓子、そろえて準備OK！
Veggie juice, fizzy drinks, and sweets, got them all ready OK!
でも朝は苦手（だねっ！）
But I'm not a morning person (right!)
夜も苦手（だねっ！）
And not a night person either (right!)
やっぱり睡眠って、大事だよね？
Sleeping really is important, huh?
たくさんの人に、愛されたいっ！
I want to be loved by lots of people!
ちゅちゅちゅっ（ちゅちゅちゅっ）
Chu chu chu! (Chu chu chu!)
大好きなみんなに、愛されたいっ！
I want to be loved by my beloved everyone!
ちゅちゅちゅっ（ちゅちゅちゅっ）
Chu chu chu! (Chu chu chu!)
そしたらなるんだ「はいぱーねねちー！」
And then I'll become hyper Nenechi!
やっちゃってねねねねねね…
Let's do it, ne-ne-ne-ne...
って、全力でいこう！そうで全開でいこう！
And go at full power! Yep, go at full throttle!
こんなこともあるけど
Sometimes things make me go through tough times,
悔しいこともあるけど
And sometimes it's frustrating,
大丈夫！
It'll be alright!
今日もしっかりおめかしして
Dressing up nicely today too,
いつかはきみと「すーぱーねねちー！」
Someday with you, super Nenechi!
ついてきてねねねねね…
Come along with me, ne-ne-ne...
って、全力でいこう！そうで全開でいこう！
And go at full power! Yep, go at full throttle!
ポンコツだっていい、誤字だっていい
Even if I'm clumsy or make a typo,
ただ駆け抜けていこうね
I'll just keep running through!
（ねっ！ねっ！ねっ！ねっ！大爆走）
(Ne! Ne! Ne! Ne! Daibakusou)
それじゃあ、またねね～！（またねね～！）
And with that, mata nene~! (Mata nene~!)
ばいば～い！
Bye-bye~!
ほっぺすてっぷじゃんぷ
Cheep, step, jump,
どるふどるふどるふどん
dolph, dolph, dolph, don,
ちっぷしろっぴほいーっぷ
chip, shiroppi, whip,
いっぱいあるもん
there's so much.
ほっぺすてっぷじゃんぷ
Cheep, step, jump,
どるふどるふどるふどん
dolph, dolph, dolph, don,
ちっぷしろっぴほいーっぷ
chip, shiroppi, whip,
なりたいあたし
the "me" I want to be.
クールで強くてカッコいい
Cool, strong, and handsome,
イケてると言われていても
even if people say I'm doing great,
本当はそんなでもないし
the truth is I'm not really like that,
フツーに女の子だもん
I'm just an ordinary girl!
プレッシャーなんかはねのけて
Brushing off the pressure,
すなおになりたいんだけど
I want to be honest, but...
キャラじゃないとか言われてさ
people say it's not my style,
あたしのこころアンロック！
unlock my heart!
なりたいようになればいいじゃん
You should be what you want to be,
シュジュキャラがついているよ
your guardian character is with you!
やりたいようにやればいいじゃん
You should do what you want to do,
ぜんぜんオッケーだし
it's totally okay!
なりたいようになればいいじゃん
You should be what you want to be,
ひとつだけじゃつまらない
being just one thing is boring.
やりたいようにやればいいじゃん
You should do what you want to do,
なんたってできるよ
after all, you can do it!
はーい、というわけで！
Alright, so!
さてさて、ここでね、みんな今日はAZKi先輩のお誕生日会だから、ここでAZKi先輩と一緒に歌っていきたいと思います！AZKi先輩！いえーい！
Now, since today is AZKi-senpai's birthday, let's sing together! AZKi-senpai, yay!
ちょっとね、ちびあず事故が起きてちゃったんですけど、
Um, a chibi-AZKi accident happened...
そこもねねちのアイドル力でカバーしてもらって...
Nenechi's idol power covered for it, though!
もうめちゃくちゃ聴きたかったその、あの2曲をね、今日ね歌ってもらえてもうしあわせ...
I really wanted to hear those two songs today, I'm so happy...
幸せでさづきはもう今日もう胸がいっぱいで...
I'm so happy, my heart is already so full today...
まだまだいっぱいこれから...
There's still more to come!
ということで、なんと今日はねねちと一緒に歌います！歌ってみたかったんだー！
And so, we get to sing together with Nenechi! I wanted to try singing this!
いやそのねねちとね何を歌おうかなと思って、今日あずきこの曲を選曲して来ました。
I wondered what to sing with Nenechi, so AZKi chose this song for today.
すごい良い曲で、でこれはあのねねちに合うと思って、なんだろう、ねねちってて元気いっぱい、わあ！
It's a wonderful song, and I thought it would suit Nenechi so well, wow!
猫になる準備はよろしいでしょうか？猫になる準備をよろしくお願いします！
Are you ready to become cats? Please get ready!
はい、ということで2人でこの曲を歌いたいと思います！では一緒にいきましょう！せーの、猫ならばいけるー！
Yes! So let's sing this together! Ready, if we're cats, we can do it!
吾輩は猫である
I am a cat,
今日も幸せで鳴いているよ
meowing happily today as well.
君君 愛し君君
You, my beloved,
吾輩と出会ってくれて有難う
thank you for meeting me.
This is a little love song.
曲名はまだ無い。
It has no title yet.
吾輩を呼ぶ声
The voice calling me,
頬を撫でていく掌
the palm stroking my cheek.
春風の様な優しさに
With a gentleness like a spring breeze,
喉が震えた
my throat trembled.
君の膝の上 今は此処が楽園である
On your lap, this place is now paradise.
ちゃんとフォロートゥイートしなくちゃじゃん 下描きなんてそんな簡単に取って
You've got to follow and tweet properly, taking drafts so easily...
完璧な140字 総勢スッテリト 心が折れる日曜日
A hundred forty characters, a stellite Sunday breaking my heart.
休みもなしに歌い続ける そんなのへっちゃら余裕だぜ みんなと一緒なら大丈夫
Continuing to sing without a break is a breeze if I'm with everyone!
だから応援よろしくね
So please support me!
本質的に甘やかして
Essentially, spoil me
毎じゃうでね！
every single day!
でも今日はやばい 本当にねもういい 猫私もうちゃんを見てほしい
But today is dangerous, really, I want you to look at Nene-chan.
推しの愛がほしい だから猫になって甘やかされたい
I want my oshi's love, so I want to become a cat and be spoiled.
吾輩は猫である
I am a cat,
甘やかされたい
I want to be spoiled.
吾輩は猫である
I am a cat,
愛されたいよ
I want to be loved.
吾輩は猫である お昼寝させて
I am a cat, let me take a nap.
起きたら100万登録いってないかな
When I wake up, will I reach 1 million subscribers?
猫ならばいける
If we're cats, we can do it!
にゃにゃにゃにゃにゃにゃにゃ
Meow meow meow meow meow!
猫猫猫猫猫 猫猫猫猫猫
Cat cat cat cat cat!
チオチオチオチオ チオチオチオチオ
Chio chio chio chio!
公園で可愛いわんちゃん見つけたよ 撫でようとしたらほえられた
Found a cute dog in the park, when I tried to pet it, it barked.
やっぱ猫になりたい
As expected, I want to be a cat!
でもどうすればいい 猫のなりかた
But what should I do? How to become a cat?
隠れない本当にしてほしい 作って作ってほしい
I want you to truly do it, I want you to make it!
吾輩は猫である 抱きしめられたい
I am a cat, I want to be hugged.
吾輩は猫である 撫で撫でしてよ
I am a cat, pet me!
吾輩は猫である 餌を与えて
I am a cat, give me food.
山盛りチュールはよろしくね
A mountain of churu, please!
猫になって恋してたいの
I want to be a cat and be in love.
猫になって笑い合おうよ
Let's become cats and laugh together!
もっとみんな猫になろうよ
Let's all become cats more!
にゃにゃにゃにゃにゃ にゃにゃにゃにゃにゃ
Meow meow meow meow meow!
みんな猫になった
Everyone became cats!
ほんとやっぱり
Honestly, as expected,
起きたら12時
when I woke up, it was noon!
ラインめっちゃきてる でも魔王じゃない
My LINE is blowing up, but it's not the Demon King.
キャくに二度寝しましょ
Let's just go right back to sleep instead!
だから 猫になって
So, I want to be a cat
猫になって甘やかされたい
and be pampered!
猫になって愛されたいよ
I want to be a cat and be loved!
猫になってお昼寝させて
Let me take a nap like a cat,
起きたら尺魔六段
and when I wake up, it's level 6!
猫になって輝きたいよ
I want to be a cat and shine bright!
猫になって大作戦するよ
I'm gonna launch a big cat operation!
もっと君に伝わりますように
I hope it reaches you even more!
もっともっと！
Even more, more!
猫になって甘やかされたいずっと
I want to be a cat and be pampered forever!
猫になって抱き締められたいもっと
I want to be a cat and be hugged tighter!
猫になって声聞かせてよ
I want to be a cat and hear your voice!
猫になって笑い合おうよ
Let's be cats and laugh together!
もっとみんな猫になろうよ
Let's all become cats more and more!
猫のロボット
A cat robot!
猫でと なら行ける！
If we're cats, we can do anything!
どこまでもついていくよ
We'll follow you anywhere!
ありがとうございました！
Thank you very much!
ありがとうございましたー！
Thank you so much!
またね！ていうていうじゃん！
See you! Or so we say!
待てが、待て今日は羊から猫になってよ。
Wait, wait, today you went from a sheep to a cat.
今日限り猫ちゃんだからさ。
Because you're a cat just for today.
ありがとうございました！ねねちとね、
Thank you so much! Nenechi and I,
この曲をね歌ったら絶対楽しいと思って。
thought singing this song together would be so much fun.
でね、今日実際にめっちゃ楽しかった！
And actually, today was super fun!
でコメントをみんなね、なんかちょうどね、あのねスタンプにゃってあるんですよ。
And in the comments, everyone, there's actually a "nya" stamp.
それでみんな、みんな猫に、猫に猫になってもらいましたー！
So we had everyone become cats!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
かわいいかった！
So cute!
めっちゃ楽しかった！わためも愛の手ありがとう！
It was super fun! Watame, thanks for the cheers too!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
猫しか言ってねえで
You only said "nya"!
猫じゃないの？
Aren't you a cat?
にゃん！
Nyan!
ということでですね、次はわためのソロパートと！
And with that, next is Watame's solo part and—
おまたせ！
Wait for it!
楽しみ！
I'm so excited!
頑張ってね！
Do your best!
頑張る！
I'll do my best!
ねねおじとAZKiするんだ。
Nene-oji and AZKi are doing it.
見てるからな。見られる側って
I'll be watching. Being the one watched...
見られる側って
Being the one watched...
こういう気持ちだったんだ！
This is what it feels like!
見られる側って！頑張って！
Being the one watched! Do your best!
いいわけだな。
That's a good excuse.
脇ストリームじゃなくて。
It's not an armpit stream.
でわ、ここからは、そのですね、頑張りたいと思う！おまため！猫からこの曲になります。
And so, from here on, we want to do our best! Watame! From cat, it turns into this song.
怪獣！なんてこった！
Monster! Oh gosh!
このふざけた素晴らしい世界に 今日も乾杯
Cheers to this ridiculous, wonderful world today as well!
町に飛び交う笑い声も 見て見ぬふりしてるだけの作りもんさ
The laughter filling the town is just a sham pretending not to notice.
気付けば暗々、クラクラするほどの切なさが
Before I knew it, a dizzying, suffocating sorrow
ツンと刺した鼻の奥 目を覚ます本能のまま今日は誰の番だ
pricked deep inside my nose; following my waking instincts, whose turn is it today?
この世界で何ができるのか
What can I do in this world?
僕には何ができるのか
What can I do?
ただその真っ黒な目から涙こぼれ落ちるように
Just like tears spilling from those pitch-black eyes,
ああ ネガティブ未来に何度でもずっと
Ah, no matter how many times in a negative future,
苦しめ この間違いだらけの世界の中
I'll keep struggling in this world full of mistakes;
君には笑ってほしいから もう誰も傷つけない
since I want you to smile, I won't hurt anyone anymore.
強く強くなりたいんだよ 僕が僕でいられるように
I want to be strong, so I can stay who I am.
素晴らしい世界は今日も安泰
This wonderful world is safe today as well,
町に渦巻く悪い話も知らない知らないふりして目を逸らした
pretending not to know the malicious rumors swirling in town, I looked away.
正気の沙汰じゃないだ
It's pure madness!
真面目に着飾った星 鳴らすなし音弾む
Stars dressed up seriously, sounding out bouncing notes;
行き先は消えない消えない 味が染みついている
my destination won't fade, its taste has soaked in.
清く正しく生きること 誰も悲しまずに生きること
Living purely and righteously, living without making anyone sad,
はみ出さず真っすぐに生きること
living straight without sticking out—
それが間違わないで生きること
that is living without mistakes;
有りのまま生きることが正義か
is living as you are justice?
だましだまし生きるのは正義か 僕の在るべき姿とはなんだ
Is living a lie justice? What is the way I ought to be?
本当の僕はなにものなんだ
What on earth am I truly?
今日も答えのない世界の中で あがってるんだよ
In this world without answers today, I'm struggling along.
不器用だけれど
Though I'm clumsy,
いつまでも君とただ笑っていたいから
I just want to keep smiling with you forever.
あぁ跳ねる心臓が体揺らし叫んだよ
Ah, my bounding heart shook my body and cried out,
今こそ勇気出せ
"Now is the time to summon your courage!"
あぁ弱い自分を何度でもずっと食い尽くすこの
Ah, repeatedly devouring my weak self,
間違いだらけの世界の中君には笑ってほしいから
in this world full of mistakes, I want you to smile.
もう誰も泣かさないよ強く強くなりたいんだよ
I won't make anyone cry anymore; I want to become strong, stronger.
僕が僕でいられるように
So that I can remain myself.
ただ君を守るそのために 走れ 走れ 走れなんだよ
Just to protect you, I must run, run, run!
僕の中の僕も変えない
I can't even change the self inside me!
隠してくだサイ！
Please hide it!
やがてくだサイ！
Please let it bloom!
恥ずかしがって！
Be embarrassed!
本来臆病で 案外泣き虫
Naturally cowardly, surprisingly a crybaby,
全然変わらず 元来君ばか
completely unchanged, originally a fool for you.
当たり前の用にキュンてしちゃう 君がいないとガッカリしちゃう
I get butterflies so naturally; without you, I feel let down.
本当の本当にしょんぼりしちゃうわ 会いたくなっちゃうな
I get truly, truly dejected and want to see you.
意外と寂しんぼ 意外と甘えんぼ
Surprisingly lonely, surprisingly clingy,
意外とお慌てんぼ 意外とテレ屋
surprisingly flustered, surprisingly shy.
丸い飛行機雲 飛び出したカップケーキ
A round vapor trail, a popped-out cupcake,
三回目のコンディショナー 余るパズル
a third conditioner, leftover puzzle pieces.
ふわふわ浮かぶ 夢見心地 一つ一つ数えて おやすみなさい
Floating fluffily, feeling like in a dream, counting one by one, good night.
密かに芽生えた このキモチ まっすぐ見つめないで
This feeling that secretly sprouted—don't stare at it straight on.
なんだったっけ 言葉にした時 きっとそうじゃない 照れちゃっただけじゃないの
What was it again? When put into words, surely that's not it, I was just too shy.
もうそうじゃないのにさ 曖昧たんじゃない この気持ちは間違いじゃないかな
Even though it's no longer like that, isn't it ambiguous? Isn't this feeling a mistake?
響きりげんま かなり同い年で
Pretty much the same age,
有効普段でも 絶対に毎日会いに来てくれるよね
even ordinarily, you'll definitely come see me every day, right?
会いに来てくれるよね？ 本気で臆病で
You'll come see me, right? Seriously cowardly,
案外泣き虫 全然変わらずに
surprisingly a crybaby, completely unchanged.
当たり前のようにキュンてしちゃう 君がいないとっかりしちゃう 本当の本当にしょんぼりしちゃうわ
I get butterflies so naturally; without you, I feel let down and truly dejected.
会いたくなっちゃうな 後悔ばっかししちゃう この心も勇気出しちゃえ この指とまれ
I want to see you, I just keep regretting. Let this heart summon courage too, grab onto this finger.
みんな来てくれて本当にお誕生日おめでとう！ありがとう！
Thank you everyone for coming, and Happy Birthday! Thank you!
青くて澄んだ空をぎゅっと抱きしめて 今日も快晴だ
Embracing the blue, clear sky tightly, today is clear and sunny again.
「知らない」はききっと怖くて 「わかる」はききっと安心できる
"Not knowing" is surely scary, while "knowing" brings comfort.
でも私が選ぶのは「ありえない」の向こう側
But what I choose is beyond the "impossible."
青くて澄んだ空を胸いっぱい吸い込んで
Breathing in the blue, clear sky deep into my chest,
透明になるまで 声を鳴らせ
I'll let my voice ring out until I become transparent.
私が誰かを照らせるなら
If I can illuminate someone,
誰かの救いになったら
if I can become someone's salvation,
奇跡の一つでも起こせるような気がするよ
I feel like I could work even a single miracle.
歌声は溶けて朝になる 悲しみごと抱いて微熱を帯びる
My singing melts into morning, embracing the sadness and catching a slight fever.
そうだ、この気持ちに名を付けるなら
That's right, if I were to name this feeling...
「アツい」はきっと端から冷めて 「定番」になれば御の字
"Hot" passions surely cool from the edges, and becoming a "classic" is a win.
せっかくならみんなでさ 笑った顔見合っていこうぜ
Since we're here, let's all exchange smiling faces together.
青くて春な夢を胸いっぱい背負い込んで 熟れた分だけ 想い出となれ
Carrying a blue, spring-like dream deep in our chests, may it become memories as it ripens.
私がただ幸せだったら
If I were merely happy,
悔やむことさえなかったら
if there was nothing even to regret,
心に眠った衝動に気付くこともないから
I would never notice the impulses sleeping in my heart.
歌声は涙に寄り添う ときめきごと抱いて微熱を帯びる
My singing cuddles close to tears, embracing the excitement and catching a slight fever.
そうだ、この気持ちに名を付けるなら
That's right, if I were to name this feeling...
花が咲けば枯れていく 種を蒔けば宿っている
Flowers bloom then wither, seeds are sown and take root;
運命に意味なんて初めから無いんじゃない?
wasn't there no meaning to fate from the very start?
咲き誇れ 散り笑え
Bloom proudly, scatter and smile!
私が誰かを照らせるなら
If I can illuminate someone,
誰かの救いになったら
if I can become someone's salvation,
奇跡の一つでも起こせるような気がするよ
I feel like I could work even a single miracle.
歌声は溶けて朝になる 悲しみごと抱いて微熱を帯びる
My singing melts into morning, embracing the sadness and catching a slight fever.
空が温かくてきれいだ 私はなんだか小春な
The sky is warm and beautiful; somehow I feel like a mild spring day—
この気持ちが愛おしくて大好きだったんだ
this feeling was so precious and I loved it so much.
名前ないこの気持ちを
This nameless feeling...
え、ここで
Eh, right here?
あの曲を… ついに！ なんだって？ あずきちゃんと一緒に！
That song... finally! What is it? Together with AZKi!
歌いたいと 思いました！ あずきちゃん！ 何を歌ってくれるの？
I wanted to sing it! AZKi-chan, what will you sing for us?
なんと！
What a surprise!
ちょっと、その前に水飲んで！水飲んで水飲んで！
Wait, drink some water before that! Drink water, drink water!
休憩タイム！ 休憩タイム！
Intermission time! Intermission time!
いや、いまそこらへんでめっちゃ聞きたかったの！いや、めっちゃ聞きたかったの！
Man, I really wanted to hear it right over there! I really wanted to hear it!
あのね、そう、実はあのあずきのちょっとあの音楽を止めるなシリーズの、あのライブのパートがあったんですけど
You see, actually, there was a live part in AZKi's "Don't Stop the Music" series,
そこでも実話、歌わせてもらったりもしていて… これもう本人、本人のもう、歌をね、
and I actually got to sing there too... And hearing the original artist's own singing—
聞きたくて、もうここ来たまである、本当に！
I wanted to hear it so badly, I've come all this way just for this, really!
緊張だよ！あずきちゃんの歌大好きだからさ！
I'm so nervous! Because I love AZKi-chan's singing!
いや本当に歌ってくれてありがとう！
Man, thank you so much for singing it!
ありがとうございます！もうなんかさ、その袖でウォーをするのが夢だったの、ちょっと。
Thank you so much! You know, doing the "Wao!" in the wings was my dream.
楽しかった！楽しかった！楽しかった！
It was fun! It was fun! It was fun!
だからね、はい、ということでね、今日はですね、なんと二人でその歌を歌いたいと…
So, yeah, that's why today, the two of us want to sing that song...
思います！
we'd love to!
おー！楽しみ！頑張るぞ！
Ooh! I'm looking forward to it! Let's do our best!
はい！というわけで一緒にタイトルコールお願いします！
Yes! So please, let's do the title call together!
聞いてください。せーの、いのち。
Please listen. Ready, set, "Inochi."
息をしている だから 生きている
I'm breathing, therefore I am alive.
何度も ずっと 言葉を尽くしてきたんだ
Time and time again, I've exhausted every word.
息をしているように 見えている
It looks as though I'm simply breathing,
青が 染み出す 私にとっての 何か
something that bleeds blue, essential to me.
鼓動が ドクドクしている
My heartbeat is thumping away.
此処は いつも 変わりなく 焦がし続ける
This place always, unchangingly, keeps yearning.
ボタン 一つの いのち
A single button's worth of life—
最後まで 私のこと 覚えていてくれる の？
will you remember me until the very end?
消えてしまいそうなの わかってよ わかってよ ねぇ
I feel like I'm about to fade away, understand me, understand me, hey.
本当のとこ どうなの？
How is it really?
いずれは 卒業するんでしょう？
Eventually, I'll graduate, right?
日常に戻ったら 私は いなくなるの
Once I return to everyday life, will I disappear?
命のような 夢を見ているよ
I'm dreaming a dream like life itself.
またね 、 バイバイ 。
See you later, bye-bye.
息をしている だから 生きている
I'm breathing, therefore I am alive.
見た目と 中身の 境界線を 跨いで 戻って
Crossing the boundary line between appearance and inner self, returning back.
音が止まって 動かなくなって
When the music stops and I can no longer move,
そんな 私を 君は 笑ってくれる かな？
I wonder if you'll smile at someone like me?
鼓動が ドクドクしている
My heartbeat is thumping away.
此処は いつも 変わりなく 巡り続ける
This place always, unchangingly, keeps revolving.
気分次第の いのち
A life driven by whims—
最後まで 私のこと 見届けてくれる の？
will you watch over me until the very end?
綻んでしまいそうなの わかってよ わかってよ ねぇ
I feel like I'm about to fray, understand me, understand me, hey.
「本当の気持ち」を 繋いだら もう二度と 戻せないのに
If we connect our "true feelings," we can never go back again, yet—
君が 忘れちゃったら 私は いなくなるの？
if you forget me, will I cease to exist?
命のような 夢を見ているよ
I'm dreaming a dream like life itself.
またね 、 バイバイ 。
See you later, bye-bye.
いき急いだ あの日を 軽く イジらないで あげて
Don't lightly tease those rushed days of the past,
それが 生きる 糧 に なる から
because they become the nourishment for living.
大丈夫 ずっと 私は 歌い続ける から
It's okay, I will keep on singing forever.
音が止まって
The sound stopped,
動かなくなって
And stopped moving,
そんな私を 君は笑ってくれるかな
I wonder if you'll laugh at someone like me.
鼓動がドクドクしている
My heart is beating heavily,
嫌われても 腐らずに ここで歌うよ 気分次第で
Even if I'm hated, I won't rot; I'll sing right here, depending on my mood.
命のような 夢を見てる
Dreaming a dream like life.
最後まで私のこと 見届けてくれるぞ
Will you watch over me until the very end?
逆さましまいそうなの 分かってよ 分かってよね
I feel like I'm turning upside down; please understand.
声が聞こえるんだよ 白いからい涙が出てじゃまそう
I can hear your voice, white, stinging tears getting in the way.
君が忘れちゃったら 私は痛くなるの 命のような
If you forget me, it will hurt—dreaming a life-like...
夢を見てる またねバイバイ
dream, see you later, bye-bye.
バイバイなんて言わないで
Don't say bye-bye.
さあ、こんだあの日を 軽くいじらないで やめて
Now, don't casually meddle with that day, stop it.
その命が広がっていくから
Because that life will keep expanding.
大丈夫 ずっと私は 歌い続けるから
It's alright, I will keep on singing forever.
最後まで私は 生きているか分からないけど
Even though I don't know if I'll be alive until the end,
君がくれた言葉は 確かに残ってる
The words you gave me certainly remain.
最後まで私のこと 覚えててくれるぞ 必死でしまうだろう
Will you remember me until the end? You'll probably struggle so hard,
分かんない 分かんないよね
You don't know, do you?
期待くらい気持ちが シンクロするときもあるけど
Though sometimes our feelings synchronize with expectations,
君が忘れちゃったら 私は痛くなるの
If you forget me, it hurts.
命のような 夢を見てる またねバイバイ
Dreaming a life-like dream, see you later, bye-bye.
いのち AZKi
[Song: Inochi - AZKi]
ありがとうございましたー！
Thank you very much!
まてすごいうたつないでくれてありがとう！
Wait, thank you so much for singing together with us!
よかったー！
I'm so glad!
めちゃくちゃ芽吹いた命がとどめ刺されちゃったよ
The sprouting life took the finishing blow!
感情になっちゃってたね 命が生まれました
You became so emotional. Life was born!
命割れました 生誕爆誕しました
Life broke! It was a birthday explosion!
はい、ということで、わためと一緒に命を歌いましたー！
Yes, so... Watame and I sang "Inochi" together!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you!
いやあ、もう結構もう胸がいっぱいなんだけど
Man, my heart is already so full...
わかるー
I know, right?
もうね今日ここに、リハーサルした時からもう結構もう、あのなんだろう、今日ありがとうって
Ever since rehearsals today, I've been feeling like... "Thank you for today."
ありがとう
Thank you!
っていう気持ちでいっぱいで、二人こうやって来てくれて、一緒に歌ってくれて、AZKiはもう胸がいっぱいです。ありがとうございます。
My heart is so full with those feelings. You two came out and sang with me, AZKi's heart is so full. Thank you!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you!
いやあ、もう帰ろっかな。ダメだダメだ！
Well, guess I'll head home. No way, no way!
まだ1曲ですよね！次がまだあるんだよ！
There's still one more song! There's still another one!
ねねソロ、わためソロ、もう満足、もう満足！
Nene's solo, Watame's solo, I'm already satisfied!
止めて止めて止めて！
Stop, stop, stop!
あ、じゃあ次はAZKiちゃんのソロパートがあります！
Ah, well next is AZKi-chan's solo part!
心を込めて、楽しみにしていてください！それではいただきます！バイバイバイバイ、ありがとー！
Please look forward to it with all our hearts! Here we go! Bye-bye-bye-bye, thank you!
ということで、ここからソロパートをそれぞれねねちとわために歌ってもらったので、ここはAZKiのソロパートを最後に歌ってですね、やっていきたいと思います。それでは聞いてください、この曲からいきます。「リアルメランコリー」
And with that, Nenechi and Watame each sang their solo parts, so now I'll sing AZKi's solo part to close it out. Please listen, starting with this song: "Real Melancholy".
答えを教えてよ リアルメランコリー
Tell me the answer, Real Melancholy.
みんなも一緒に！イェーイ！
Everyone together too! Yay!
体と感情が交差する
Body and emotions intersect,
ただしい自分は何？
What is the correct self?
糸と糸を繋いで 交差する世界は
Connecting thread to thread, the intersecting world
今はひとつじゃない
is no longer just one.
行き交うファボの数だけ 増えていく
Just by the number of passing favorites, it grows.
無機質なゼロを振りかざして 首を絞める
Wielding lifeless zeros, choking my neck.
私の生きる世界は自分の手で選ばせてよ
Let me choose the world I live in with my own hands!
真夜中のメランコリー 生まれ変わるアイデンティティ
Midnight melancholy, a reborn identity.
好み がこの辺が 痛いよ
This taste, this area hurts so much,
普遍的なオルタナティブ 順守してく可愛いフェイス
A ubiquitous alternative, maintaining a cute face.
私は 私は 誰かにとって 変わるの？
To someone, am I... changing?
理想と現実が交差する
Ideal and reality intersect,
ただしい私は何？
What is the correct me?
再生回数が落ちてゆく
The view count is dropping.
世界は どこも同じだ
The world is the same everywhere.
キャラ属性カテゴライズ されていく 誰かに気付けられたような 流行り廃りなんて
Categorized by character traits... Trends like being noticed by someone,
新しい やりたいことは 自分の手で決めさせてよ
Let me decide what new things I want to do with my own hands!
真夜中のメランコリー 生まれ変わるアイデンティティ
Midnight melancholy, a reborn identity.
好み がこの辺が 痛いよ
This taste, this area hurts so much,
同じじゃない この想い 私たちは 誰かにとって 変わるの？
These feelings aren't the same. To someone, will we change?
早すぎる どちらも欲しい 矛盾の文字と繰り返していく
Too fast, wanting both, repeating with contradictory words.
ナン番目のコピーじゃないの 永遠の夜を超えてく
Not a copy N, transcending the eternal night,
未知なる世界へ
to an unknown world.
一人目の手を繋いで
Holding hands with the first person,
真夜中のメランコリー 生まれ変わるアイデンティティ
Midnight melancholy, a reborn identity.
だけどね 私は一人じゃない
But you know, I'm not alone.
あなたと似た世界の君へ エールを送るよ 私のために
To you in a world similar to yours, I send cheers, for my own sake.
真夜中のメランコリー 生まれ変わるアイデンティティ
Midnight melancholy, a reborn identity.
好み がこの辺が 痛いけど どこかの世界の君へ
This taste hurts around here, but to you in some world,
私と似た気持ちの君へ エールを送るよ
to you with feelings similar to mine, I send cheers.
君とたちのために
For you and me.
愛が言葉を見失ってる
Love is losing words.
空が涙を降らせていたんだ
The sky was making tears fall.
誰のために 何のために 出会う運命というの？
For whose sake, for what sake is it called a destiny to meet?
嘘が街を包み込んでいる
Lies are wrapping around the town.
鳥がとべずに目を上げていた
Birds couldn't fly and raised their eyes.
たった一つの存在を灯す
Lighting a single existence.
この場所で君を待ってる
I'm waiting for you in this place.
世界はとても苦しそうでした 私に何ができるというの？
The world looked so painful. What can I do?
歌うことが正しいかなんて 今も答えは見つからないけど
Whether singing is right or not, I still can't find the answer,
確かなのは君がいたから 私はここにいるの
but what is certain is that because you were here, I am here.
長い何度だって君と出会うから 夜が明けていく光
Because I'll meet you over and over through long times, the light as the night breaks.
答え教えてよ
Tell me the answer,
リアルメランコリー
real melancholy.
身体と感情が交差する
Body and emotions intersect.
正しい自分は何？
What is the true self?
二と三を繋いで 交差する
Connecting two and three, intersecting—
世界は一つじゃない
the world is not just one.
いいね good ファボの数字増えていく
"Likes" and "good" favorites keep increasing.
盲目に 正論 振りかざして首を絞める
Blindly waving righteousness, choking myself.
その一瞬が煌めく yeah
That single moment sparkles, yeah.
過去が道を壊したとしても
Even if the past destroyed the path,
夢が街をくらい尽くしたとしても
even if dreams devoured the city completely,
大丈夫だから
it'll be okay,
そばにいるよ 君に笑ってほしいんだ
so I'm right by your side, I want you to smile.
生まれた意味を探しているの
Searching for the meaning of why I was born,
このままでもただ走り続けていく
I will just keep running forward like this.
今を知って
Knowing the present,
明日をたたえた
praising tomorrow—
心が叫びたがってる
my heart is screaming out.
タイムマシンに乗ってさ 別の未来を選べたなら
If I could take a time machine and choose a different future,
君のいない世界を創造する？ そんな世界は創造できない
would I create a world without you? No, such a world is unimaginable.
君に届きますように…
Hoping it reaches you...
この声がこの歌が
this voice, this song,
長い何十回だって君を選ぶから
no matter how many dozens of times, I will choose you.
夜が滲んでゆく 地平の彼方へ
Night bleeds toward the horizon,
響く呼吸の音を 確かに感じた
I surely felt the sound of breathing echoing.
始めよう君との未来を 辛いだってを離さないで
Let's start our future, never let go of the pain—
大きな声で名前を呼んで
Call out my name with a loud voice,
奇跡を駆け抜けて どこまでも行けるよ
rushing through miracles, we can go anywhere.
ここからも一度 君と私で始めよう
From here once more, you and I will begin.
無限の中に生まれる物語を 君と歩いていく
Walking with you through the story born in infinity.
この世界が悲しみに溢れたとしても
Even if this world overflows with sadness,
私は歌を歌い続けていく
I will keep on singing songs.
君と生きるここでこの場所で
Living with you here, in this very place,
それが私の世界だ
that is my world.
傷つき涙を流し 君が幸せだと思える世界になりますように
May it become a world where you can wipe away tears and feel happy.
願いを込めた歌
A song filled with my wish.
最高だー！あずず先輩！
That was amazing, Azuzu-senpai!
ありがとうございましたー！
Thank you very much!
最高！ありがとー！
Awesome! Thank you!
はい、ということでAZKiソロパートはリアルメランコリー、インディーズワールドの2曲をお届けいたしました。
So, AZKi's solo part delivered two songs: "Real Melancholy" and "Indie's World."
そしてそして皆さん見てください！新しい…これですね、AZKiのセカンド衣装なんですけれども、こうちょっとね、あの新衣装になってからちょっとそれに、それに合わせてなんと新しくしてもらいましたー！
And everyone, please look! This new... second outfit of mine, since becoming the new outfit, they adjusted and made it brand new for us!
最高ー！
Awesome!
最高！ありがと！
Awesome! Thank you!
どうですか？どうですか？
How is it? How is it?
すごい！すごい！すごい！すごい！ありがとうございまーす！
Amazing! Amazing! Thank you so much!
ねねおじ、ありがとう！
Nene-oji, thank you!
いい足！わたおしありがとう！
Nice legs! Thanks for the support!
はい、ということでね、あのね、パッパにね、ちゃんとこうちょっとまたお召し立て綺麗にしてもらいましたー！
Yes, so... Papa nicely tailored and made it clean for us!
ていうことでね、みなさんね、ちょっとね、今日ね、まるまるお披露目っていうね、あのサムネにあったんですけれども、
So everyone, today's thumbnail said "complete unveiling,"
ちびあずと、おもいけや！なんとこちらセカンド衣装、新しいセカンド衣装のお披露目でしたー！
Chibi AZKi, and surprise! It was actually the unveiling of the new second outfit!
グッジョブ！グッジョブ！グッジョブ！
Good job! Good job! Good job!
みんなスクショ撮ったほうがいいんじゃないの！？
Everyone should take screenshots, right!?
こういう気持ちになるんだ…お疲れ見てねよ！ありがとう！
This is how it feels... Good work, everyone! Thank you!
はい、ということで、えっとですね、実はまだお知らせが、なんとふたつ！
Yes, and actually, there are still two announcements!
ありがとうございます、なんちゃって！
Thank you very much, just kidding!
ありがとうございます。
Thank you.
では、1つ目の画像をお願いします。どん！
Now, please show us the first image. Boom!
期間限定受注 AZKi生誕グッズ2021
[Limited Pre-order: AZKi Birthday Goods 2021]
本日よりAZKiの生誕記念グッズ2021の受注開始いたします！
Pre-orders for AZKi's 2021 birthday merchandise begin today!
最高！イェーイ！
Awesome! Yay!
なんと、そう、あのね、新しい衣装になってからグッズがなんと初めてなんですけれども、
This is actually our first time releasing merchandise in our new outfits,
今回ですね、3つあります。
and this time, we have three items available.
1つ目はしまだ先生描き下ろしのB2タペストリー！
First is a B2 tapestry illustrated by Shimada-sensei!
欲しい！
I want it!
キラキラ、キラキラな...
A sparkling, dazzling...
次、2つ目、二ノ本先生描き下ろしのちびAZKiラバーキーホルダーセットです！
Next, second, is the chibi AZKi rubber keychain set!
なんと4種類入っておりますよ。
It actually includes four different types.
お得！お得！
Such a bargain! A bargain!
ちびAZKiも早速ね、グッズになりました。早い、早い、今日初めてこうね、動いたんですけど。
Chibi AZKi has already become merchandise too! It's so fast, today is the first time we've moved like this.
えーっと、こちらもちろろしくお願いします。
Please look forward to this one as well.
そして最後に、3つ目のアクリルスタンドです！
And finally, the third item is the acrylic stand!
欲しい！買うしかない！
I want it! I have to buy it!
えー、こちらですね、すべてこのあと21時からAZKiオフィシャルストアにて受注販売開始いたします。
All of these will be available for pre-order starting at 21:00 tonight on the AZKi Official Store.
8月3日までの1ヶ月間の期間限定になるので、
Since it's a limited time of one month until August 3rd,
ぜひこの機会に買ってください。
please be sure to buy them during this opportunity.
急げ！今すぐ買え！ありがとう！急げ！
Hurry! Buy them right now! Thank you! Hurry!
ということで、さて、もう一つのおしらせなんですが、重大発表画像お願いします！
With that said, now for another announcement, please show the major announcement image!
NEXT... AZKi 8th LIVE Rewind & Reunion
[Title: AZKi 8th LIVE Rewind & Reunion]
どーん！なんと！解禁になっておりました！AZKi 8th LIVE リワインド＆リユニオンの開催が9月12日、池袋harevutaiに決まりました！
Boom! It has been unveiled! AZKi 8th LIVE 'Rewind & Reunion' is officially decided for September 12 at Ikebukuro Harevutai!
すごい！おめでとう！解禁になってたんですけど、ついに来た！
Amazing! Congratulations! It was already announced, but it's finally here!
はい、今回ですね、9月12日に開催が決まりました。
Yes, this time, the event has been decided for September 12.
まだね、ちょっと、まだ、あの情勢がね、わからないところなんですけど、みんなとやっと再開できる場所としてこの日を作りました。
We still don't know what the situation will be like, but we created this day as a place where we can finally reunite with everyone.
2019年のね、12月29日にアズリンネで止まってしまった時をですね、みんなで一緒にもう一度動かし始められたらって思っていますので、ぜひぜひ来てくれたら嬉しいです。
We hope to restart the time that stopped on December 29, 2019, together with everyone, so we'd be so happy if you come.
チケットなどの詳細は来月お知らせできると思うので、お楽しみに！ということで、お知らせ2つでした！
Details about tickets should be announced next month, so look forward to it! So those were our two announcements!
絶対行くよ！行くよ！
We're definitely going! We're going!
ありがとう！じゃあね、二人カモンカモン！
Thank you! Come on, you two, come on!
お邪魔します！
Pardon us!
わあ、すごーい！やったー！おめでとう！
Waah, amazing! Yay! Congratulations!
おお、いい匂い。
Oh, it smells nice.
この姿も好きですか？お邪魔していいんですか？可愛い！
Do you like this look too? Is it okay for us to barge in? So cute!
いいんですか？どうなさってんの？どうなさってんの？
Is this okay? What's going on with you? What's going on?
どうなさってんですか？最高。どうなさってんですか？
What is this? This is the best. What's going on?
二人でね、ねえ、ねえ。お邪魔しますって。
Just the two of us, hey, hey. 'Pardon us,' we said.
はい、ということで、今日はもう森だくさんの、すごい、あの、おじさんが二人います。
So, today we have a packed stream with... two old men here.
はい、今日森だくさんのね、ねねちにね、ねねちね、今浴びてる！
Yes, Nenechi, who has a lot going on today... you're bathing in it right now!
ネネチのソロパートと、最初はね、二人でね、シャイニースマイルストリート歌ってね、ネネチのソロパート！
Nenechi's solo part, and first the two of us sang 'Shiny Smiled Street', Nenechi's solo part!
そして、ネネチと一緒にネコならばいける歌ったあと！
And after singing 'If You're a Cat, You Can Do It' with Nenechi!
おためえのソロパート、命をね、歌いましたね。
Then Watame's solo part, singing 'Inochi' (Life).
そしてAZKiのソロパートとなってまして、3人ね、ね？3人ね、ここに集まったんだから。
And then AZKi's solo part, and since the three of us gathered here...
最後の曲、3人で、いいですか？歌いましょうか？
Shall the three of us sing the final song? Is that okay? Shall we sing it?
あ、ちょっと、その前にちょっと着替えます。どうやって？え？すごい！新衣装だ！最後の衣装！
Ah, wait, before that, let's change clothes. How? Eh? Amazing! A new outfit! The final outfit!
はい、着替えてまいりました。はい、今日はね本当に改めて、こんなにね、かわいいかわいいねえ。
Yes, we've changed clothes. Yes, today really, once again, looking so cute, cute.
かわいいね、かわいいね。
So cute, so cute.
はい、二人と一緒に生誕ライブができてめちゃくちゃ幸せな、本当に、え、お誕生日にになりました。ありがとう、二人とも。
Yes, being able to hold this birthday live together with the two of you makes me so happy. It truly became a wonderful birthday. Thank you both.
ありがとう！
Thank you!
いやこうやってね、なんか、初めの誕生日のときはこんなふうにゲスト呼んだりとか、なんか、する未来が全然なんかこう、予測もしてなかったので、なんか今日こうやって二人と一緒にライブできて嬉しいです。
I never expected or imagined in the future that for my first birthday I'd invite guests like this, so I'm so happy we could do a live together today.
これからもっと、エモ、エモが重すぎる。
From now on, more... emo, the emo is too overwhelming.
いやなんかこうやってね、本当に、なんか一緒に、なんだろう、歌える日が来るなんてという気持ちでいっぱいなので、これからも、なんだろう、また一緒に歌ってください。
I'm so filled with feelings of 'to think a day would come where we could sing together like this,' so please continue to sing together with me.
いやこちら！
No, us too!
もちろん！
Of course!
言ってください！
Please say it!
次もお願いします！
Please do the next one too!
すごーい！すごい！45度以上！
Amazing! Amazing! Over 45 degrees!
写真を流しました！写真を流しました！
I streamed the photos! I streamed the photos!
ということで、これからもね、なんか、それぞれがね、歌ね、オリジナル曲とか出してて、がんばっているので、あずきもがんばっていきたいと思いますと、思います！
And so, going forward, everyone is releasing original songs and working hard, and AZKi wants to do her best too! I think!
それでは、
Now then,
最後の曲、いきますか！
shall we go to the last song?
はーい！
Yay!
いくか！
Let's go!
では、3人でタイトルコールしましょう！
Now, let's do the title call together as three!
聞いてください、せーの！
Listen up, ready, go!
キラメキライダー☆！
Kirameki Rider☆!
生まれたてのドキドキを響かせようよ
Let's make our newborn heartbeat resonate,
最高の時間 最高の仲間と
with the best times and the best friends,
キラメキに乗って☆
riding on the sparkle☆
イエーイ
Yeah!
キラメキライダー☆
Kirameki Rider☆
覚えているかな？最初の歌（なつかしいね）
Do you remember? Our very first song (how nostalgic)
私の声が震えてた（ほんの少し）
My voice was trembling (just a little bit)
あの日から続く未来は
The future that has continued since that day
みんなと掴んだ今日だよ
is today, which we grasped together with everyone!
もっともっともっともっともっと加速するハート
Our hearts accelerate more and more, more and more!
（いっしょに）行こうどこまでも（are you ready？）
(Together) we'll go anywhere (Are you ready?)
準備はOK？
Is everyone ready?
ひらめき！！夢のトビラを
Unfold!! The door of dreams
（123） キラメキライダー☆
(1, 2, 3) Kirameki Rider☆
生まれたてのドキドキを響かせようよ
Let's make our newborn heartbeat resonate,
最高の時間 最高の仲間と ここにいるよ
with the best times and the best friends, we're right here!
見つけてくれたから 君に出会いたくてやってきたんだ みんなで歌おう
Because you found us, we came wanting to meet you, let's sing together!
終わらない メロディ キラメキに乗って☆
An endless melody, riding on the sparkle☆
届いてるかな？ 私の声（はっきりと）
Is it reaching you? My voice (clearly)
届けたいのはきみに笑顔（そのスマイル！）
What I want to deliver to you is a smile (that smile!)
理想の遠さに悔しくて みんなで泣き笑ったね
Frustrated by how far our ideal was, we cried and laughed together, didn't we?
ぎゅっとぎゅっとぎゅっとぎゅっと全部抱きしめて
Tightly, tightly, tightly, tightly embracing everything,
（いっしょに）行こうどこまでも（are you ready？）
(Together) let's go anywhere (Are you ready?)
準備はOK？
Is everyone ready?
すすめ！！希望の道を
Press onward!! Down the path of hope
（123） キラメキライダー☆
(1, 2, 3) Kirameki Rider☆
好きな気持ち カラフルに奏でたいな
I want to play my favorite feelings colorfully,
最高の場所 最高の仲間と ここにいるよ
in the best place, with the best friends, we're right here!
幻なんかじゃない きみのココロが幸せに染まるように
It's no illusion, so that your heart may be dyed with happiness,
重ねてく ハーモニー キラメキまとめて☆
weaving harmonies together, gathering all the sparkle☆
歌い続けたいな 踊り続けたいな そんな願いやワガママもいいでしょ？
I want to keep singing, I want to keep dancing, such wishes and selfishness are fine, right?
だって楽しすぎて！もう止まらない！！輝くステージで
Because it's too fun! It won't stop anymore!! On the shining stage,
もっともっと！！（お願い）ずっと！！（おー いぇーい）
more and more!! (Please) forever!! (Oh yeah!)
嬉しい 楽しい 愛しい だけ じゃ 語れない 今 も 今 も 悩み は ある けど
Happy, fun, lovely—words alone cannot describe it; even now, even now, there are worries, but...
ここ に いる よ 私 ここ に いる よ きみ と 同じ 世界 を 見つめ て
I'm right here, I'm right here, gazing at the same world as you!
嬉しい 楽しい 愛しい だけじゃ語れない
Happy, fun, lovely—words alone cannot express it,
今も今もあるけど ここにいるよ 私ここにいるよ
Even now, even now, there are worries, but I'm right here, I'm right here!
きみと同じ世界を 見つめていこうよ
Let's gaze at the same world as you!
キラメキライダー☆
Kirameki Rider☆
生まれたてのドキドキを響かせようよ
Let's make our newborn heartbeat resonate,
最高の時間 最高の仲間と ここにいるよ
with the best times and the best friends, we're right here!
見つけてくれたから 君に出会いたくてやってきたんだ みんなで歌おう
Because you found us, we came wanting to meet you, let's sing together!
終わらない メロディ キラメキに乗って☆
An endless melody, riding on the sparkle☆
あさき、せーの、お誕生日おめでとう！
AZKi, ready, happy birthday!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
おめでとうございまーす！
Congratulations!
あさきちゃんの誕生日だ！これからもよろしくね！
It's AZKi's birthday! Here's to more ahead!
よろしくね、よろしくねー！
Looking forward to it, looking forward to it!
ありがとうございましたー！ありがとうございましたー！
Thank you very much! Thank you very much!
本日は、AZKi超生誕祭2021をご覧いただき、ありがとうございました！
Thank you for watching the AZKi Super Birthday Festival 2021 today!
ぜひ感想を「#AZKi超生誕祭2021」でつぶやいてください！1つ1つ大切に読みにいきます！
Please share your thoughts with "#AZKiSuperBirthday2021"! I'll read every single one!
ということで、ねねちと、わため、ありがとうございましたー！めちゃくちゃめちゃくちゃ幸せな生誕祭になりました！
So Nenechi and Watame, thank you so much! This turned out to be such a happy birthday festival!
楽しかったー！普通に、普通に楽しい、あのオタクをして、オタクをしながら一緒に歌うという、これ以上ない喜びを…最高の時間でした！
It was so fun! Just doing normal, fun otaku stuff, singing together while being otaku—pure joy... It was the best time!
ありがとうございました！また、また一緒に何か歌ったりライブしたりできる日を楽しみにしております！
Thank you so much! I look forward to the day we can sing or perform live together again!
しゃくさん、頑張ります！
Shaku-san, I'll do my best!
はい、それではじゃあみんなでバイバイで締めたいと思います！
Yes, so let's wrap things up with a wave goodbye from everyone!
はい！それでは、バイバーイ！バイバーイ！
Yes! So, bye-bye! Bye-bye!
○○初お披露目!? 重大発表!? コラボ3D LIVE!! 超生誕祭2021
[○○ First Reveal!? Major Announcement!? Collab 3D LIVE!! Super Birthday Festival 2021]